This is your mother's strong suit.
你看这就是你妈强项
All talk and no action.
光动嘴不动手
Sit.
坐
Alright, all the dishes are served.
行 这就齐了
I'll make a toast?
我提一杯啊
Okay, come.
好 来
Okay.
好
Shen,
小沈啊
you came to our house
今天是头一回
for the first time,
来我们家啊
so you need to do as I say.
所以得听我的
You drink the white one,
你喝白的
and we drink red wine.
咱们喝红的啊
Come on, cheers.
来 干一个
Dad.
爸
Shen Qingyuan is an athlete.
沈清源是运动员
He cannot drink alcohol.
不能喝酒
Look how worried she is.
看你把她给着急的
I tell you what,
我跟你说
it's just water.
放的是白水
I know he's an athlete,
知道小沈是运动员
so the fish and the meat,
所以今天这些鱼啊肉啊
and all the other dishes
所有这些菜
were selected by the dietary standard
都是按照运动员的标准
for athletes.
来配的
I spent
我刚才
so much time at the market
花那么多时间在菜市场
selecting the ingredients.
就是特地去买菜
I forgot the green cabbage.
忘了炒青菜了
Alright, alright.
行了 行了
The kids are still growing.
孩子们长身体
Fish and meat are good enough.
吃鱼 肉就可以了
Good enough?
行吗
Good enough.
行
Thank you, Mr. Tang.
谢谢叔叔
Thank you, Mom.
谢谢妈
Good.
好
- Very good, very good. - Wait.
真好真好 那这
Why not Dad?
这爸去哪儿了呢
Thank you, Dad.
谢谢爸
That's more like it.
这就对了
Come on.
来
Happy New Year!
新年快乐
She really doesn't need my help?
真不用我帮忙
No.
不用
You go talk to my dad.
你去跟我爸聊会儿天
But the guidebook for meeting the parents says
可是见家长手册上说
that during the first visit,
第一次来
the boy's supposed to help with the household chores.
要多帮忙做家务
You clean the table
那你就去擦擦桌子
and mop the floor, then.
拖拖地什么的
I'd like to do the chores with you.
我想跟你一起做家务
Do you honestly think I want to wash the dishes?
你以为我真想刷碗呢
My mom just wants
是我妈要拉着我
to have a girl-to-girl talk with me.
说悄悄话
Stay out of it.
你就别添乱了
Mom.
妈
Come on, let me help you.
来 我帮帮你
No, no. Don't get your hands dirty.
不用不用 别沾手了
It's dirty. It's dirty.
脏 脏 脏
I'm sure you're tired.
你也辛苦了啊
No, no. Honestly.
真的不用 不用
What about this? You don't touch them.
这样吧 你也别洗了
Later,
待会儿
your dad is going to wash them.
让你爸爸来洗行吗
Qingyuan,
姐夫
play game with me.
玩游戏啊
Fine.
行
But I'll clean up the table first.
不过等我先收拾下桌子
Okay.
好
I wonder where Tang Xin
我姐姐练得这是什么
learned how to tame the boyfriend.
高级的驯夫术啊
Amazing.
这么厉害
Left. Left.
左边 左边
Left, Qingyuan.
左边 姐夫
On the left.
左边
You see that?
看到没有
On the hill.
那个山头上
At the position of 345.
三四五方向
He's hiding in the bushes.
蹲着呢 草里
Right. Shoot him, shoot him.
对 打打打
Shoot him, shoot him. Quickly.
打打打 快快快
Run, run, run.
跑 跑 跑
He's coming.
跑过来了
Shoot him. Shoot him. Shoot him.
打他 打他 打他
I hit him.
我打到了
Just give him a lethal shot.
你再补他一枪就好了
A lethal shot. Yeah, yeah.
补他一枪 对对对
I'll bomb him.
我扔个雷给他
Again.
这又
Died again, Qingyuan.
又没了 姐夫
Qingyuan, I died again.
姐夫 我没了
You're on your own.
只能靠你了
Qingyuan, I get it.
姐夫 我明白了
It's not that you have talent in shooting.
你不是射击天赋高
You're just a fast learner.
你是学习力强
I think
我觉得
you can spend more time on mobile games
你平常空闲的时间
when you're free.
你可以多玩玩游戏啊
They're great.
特别好
They help with stress and depression.
又减压还抗抑郁
I won.
赢了
Awesome.
这么厉害
Five kills.
杀五个
Nice work.
可以
When you're back in Haiya,
等到时候回海雅
we'll play the game together.
我们再继续一起玩
I'll carry you to the rank of Super Ace.
我带你上超级王牌
Scheduled.
安排
No problem.
必须的
Shen.
小沈啊
Let's talk.
来
No, no. Don't get up.
坐 坐 坐
You will be with your parents on the Spring Festival's Eve?
这三十和父母一块过
They are abroad.
他们都在国外
Then how about you and Tang Xin
那三十
celebrate it at home with us?
和心心一块回家过
In the future,
以后啊
whether it's a festival or not,
甭管是不是过年过节
you're always welcome
只要你想来
to come.
随时欢迎
Just treat us as your own family.
把这儿当成自个儿的家
Okay.
知道了
Thank you, Mr. Tang.
谢谢叔叔
Dad.
叫爸
Thank you, Dad.
谢谢爸
That's right.
这就对了
My daughter,
你说你这孩子
I bet you've learned everything about life
是不是一个人在外头
now that you're having an independent life.
什么活都学会干了吧
Look at you,
看你这样
my poor girl.
你妈我心疼
Not everything.
也不全是
Alright.
行了
I haven't
妈妈今天
taken a good look at you.
还没好好看过你呢
Let me check.
我看看
You've got a little bit chubbier.
胖了点
Oh, I remember.
对了 我想起来了
The last time we went to shoe-shopping was a year ago.
我都一年没陪你买鞋了
You're wearing old shoes, right?
这鞋是旧的吧
No.
没有
Shen Qingyuan bought these for me.
沈清源跟我买的
They're really fit.
特别合脚
Look.
你看
Really?
真的
Is he nice to you?
他对你好不好
Very nice.
特别好
Glad to know.
那就好
And listen.
还有啊
Are you living together?
你俩同住了没有
Um…
那个
Um what?
这个那个的
Still hiding from me?
你还想瞒着我是不是
I'm not an old-fashioned mother.
你妈我没那么保守
It's okay that you're living together.
住一块就住一块呗
But I tell you what.
但是啊我跟你说啊
You'd better keep an eye out.
你啊还是得留个心眼
You mustn't be careless.
别大大咧咧的
Do you hear me?
听见没有
And I know you're soft-hearted.
还有 你性子软
So you mustn't be obedient.
别太听话
Don't act like a good girl.
别太老实了
Because after you're married,
到时候结了婚以后啊
the husband
男人啊
doesn't really care about the wife anymore.
是不会心疼女人的
You hear me?
听见没有
I got it, Mom.
知道了 妈
But seriously.
说点正事
I won't be staying at home
我这次回来呢
long this time.
可能待不了两天
We may
也可能
head back to Haiya tomorrow.
明天就要回海雅了
Unbelievable,
你说你这孩子啊
you just came home for one dinner?
吃顿饭你就走了啊
Listen, Mom.
好了 妈
Don't feel bad.
不难过啊
When Shen Qingyuan and I
等我跟沈清源
are settled in that city,
在那边稳定下来
you're welcome to enjoy your retirement over there.
就接你跟爸过去养老
Okay.
行
Remember.
女儿 记住了啊
Take good care of yourself out there.
在外面好好照顾自己
Come on, let me hug you.
来 让妈妈抱抱
We haven't hugged for ages.
好久没抱了啊
Won't you stay for a few more days?
真不多住几天
You old fool, our daughter is an adult now.
懂什么呀 孩子大了
Dad, Mom,
爸 妈
we're off.
那我们走了啊
Come.
来
Take care.
多保重啊
Be safe.
注意安全
Bye.
走了
Bye, Mom.
走了 妈
Bye, Mr. Tang.
走了 叔叔
Bye.
走了
Dad.
爸
Attaboy.
这差不多
Be safe, you two.
那慢点啊 你们慢点
See you. Bye-bye.
再见 拜拜
Safe travels.
慢点 慢点啊
Bye-bye. Bye-bye.
拜拜 拜拜 拜拜
How do you feel?
感觉怎么样
Our mom and dad are nice.
咱爸妈挺好的
Still Mom and Dad?
你人前人后都改称呼啊
Yeah.
对啊
I'm a man
我就是这么一个
of consistency.
表里如一的人啊
I deserve a reward, don't you think?
是不是应该奖励我一下
Why did you poke my face?
戳我干吗
You've finished your mission.
你都完成盖章任务了
Do you really need a stamp on the pork?
还差一个猪肉戳吗
Of course, I do.
我当然着急了
Wait, what pork?
谁是猪肉啊
Hello?
喂
Pretty good.
挺好的
She is with me.
她在
Dad wants to talk to you.
咱爸找你
We just left.
不是刚走吗
What's this phone call about?
怎么又打电话
Hello, Dad.
喂 爸
I'm happy
你这么叫我
that you call me this way.
我挺开心的
Mr. Shen.
沈叔叔
No need to change it.
不用改口啊
That's pretty good.
这不是挺好的嘛
Tang Xin,
小唐啊
I need to talk to you.
我要跟你说件事啊
I will soon
我这边呢
have an emergency meeting,
有一个紧急会议
and I can't really leave.
可能暂时抽不开身
Qingyuan's mother
清源他妈妈呢
is up to her neck
也是现在忙得
as well.
脚不沾地的
You may need to take care of Qingyuan
估计清源呢还得靠你
for a bit longer.
多照顾一段时间
You know
你是知道的
the foreign holidays
现在这个国外的节日呢
are different from ours.
跟国内不太一样
Now is
现在国外
the busiest season here.
正是最忙的时候
Don't worry, Mr. Shen.
放心吧 叔叔
I'll take good care of him.
我会照顾好他的
Thank you.
谢谢啊
That's it.
话不多说
His mother and I will rush back home
我跟他妈妈这边忙完了
as soon as the peak season is over.
会尽快赶回国内
By then,
我们到时候
the first thing is that we meet each other, okay?
第一时间见面 好吗
Sure, Mr. Shen.
好的 叔叔
Tang Xin,
小唐啊
you two be good.
你跟清源都要好好的
Bye, Mr. Shen.
叔叔再见
Bye.
再见
How...
感觉
do you feel?
怎么样
Dad is pretty nice.
咱爸挺好
Tang Xin,
唐心
I remember you told me
我记得你跟我说过
about the 99%
百分之九十九
and 1%.
跟百分之一的事
I used to think
以前的我
that I could
总觉得那百分之九十九
deal with 99%
生活的日常
of the daily life
可以用解决问题的态度
like I was solving problems,
去应对
or that I could deal with them without care.
或者说应付一下就好了
Maybe at the time,
或许是那个时候
I always tended
我一直把自己
to place myself at the center of a circle,
放在圆心的
the 1% part,
百分之一的位置
to observe the world.
来观察这个世界
But after I came to Yongcheng with you,
可跟你来到永城之后
I felt like
我突然觉得
once I relieve myself of the stress,
放下比赛的负担
and walk out of the center of the circle
从圆心中走出来
to embrace life,
好好地面对生活
the 99%
那百分之九十九
can be dealt with in better ways,
会有更好的解决方式
and the small things in life
生活中的点点滴滴呢
are worth being cherished.
同样值得被珍惜
The 99%
那百分之九十九
isn't the target
并不是需要
that needs to be dealt with,
被解决掉的目标
but the motivation
而可能是
for the 1%.
那百分之一的动力
Are you ready
那你准备好
for the 1% now?
迎接那百分之一了吗
I am.
准备好了
Let's go home.
回家吧
Mr. Zhang.
张教练
Hello. Hi.
你好 你好 你好
I'm Xu Dian.
我徐典
Here's the thing.
是这样啊
Your winter training
你们冬训
will soon be over, right?
不是快结束了嘛
We're going to shoot the ending part.
我们准备去拍个收尾
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
是 是 是
It is a shame
沈清源不在队里
that Shen Qingyuan isn't on the team.
是有点遗憾
But other shooters
但是其他队员
also deserve the attention, right?
也是需要关怀的嘛
Okay, okay. Sure.
好好好 行
See you around.
那回见啊
Later.
再见
The holidays were so short.
假期过得太快
They were over in the blink of an eye.
一眨眼就没了
Tell me about it.
谁说不是呢
I wonder how Captain Shen is doing.
也不知道沈队怎么样
Without Captain Shen,
感觉没有沈队的日子
I always feel like we're missing something.
总感觉像缺了点什么
Oh, right.
对了
Xu Dian is coming again
徐典好像又要来
to shoot the ending part of the winter training.
拍咱们冬训的结尾了
Xu Dian is coming again?
徐典又要来
Fine.
行
We'll sort him out
那就带着他和周越
along with Zhou Yue.
一块收拾
We'll smack them in their faces with our good scores.
用成绩打他们脸就是了
They're here.
来了
Zhou,
小周
I was just about to interview you.
刚好我要采访你
You go set the cameras.
你们去架机器
You two, prepare the interview.
你们两个准备采访
Zhou Yue.
周越选手
Ever since Shen Qingyuan left
自从沈清源选手
the winter training base,
离开冬训基地之后
you've been the first place.
你的成绩一直占据第一
So the voices online
所以现在网上
regard you
普遍声音认为
as the most promising shooter.
你才是未来的射击之星
How do you respond to that?
那你怎么看
I'm overrated.
不敢当 不敢当
You know, I feel sorry
其实这次沈清源的离开
that Shen Qingyuan left.
我表示也很惋惜
But it can't be helped
但是没有办法
because it's a psychological problem.
如果是心理有问题的话
He just
那确实没有办法
cannot be a shooter anymore.
再继续射击了
So I wish
所以我只能祝愿他
him to do well
在其他地方
in other territories.
继续发光发热
I, however, only wish to do well
在赛场上
in competitions.
发光发热就好了
Captain Shen!
沈队
- Captain! - Captain Shen!
队长 沈队
Make way.
让一下
catching people off guard
你也太喜欢
is your thing, huh?
搞突然袭击了吧
Why didn't you two
你说你们俩这突然回来
give us a notice about your return?
咋也不打声招呼啊
- Right. - Yeah.
就是啊 就是啊
Shen Qingyuan,
沈清源
you look good.
看着状态不错
Captain Shen, you came back at last.
沈队 你终于回来了
If you didn't,
你要是再不回来
I would get another partner.
我可就换搭档了
Yeah, I'm back.
回来了
Captain,
队长
lead us to the training.
带我们训练吧
Hai.
海哥
What are you talking about?
怎么就训练了呢
Yeah.
是啊
We need to hold some kind of a
咱们得搞点什么
welcome ceremony.
欢迎仪式
Right.
对啊
But we
但是咱们
didn't make any preparation.
什么都没准备啊
Hey, that's not cool.
怎么这样
Wait, let me think.
不行 我想想
Acting too carefully
表现得小心翼翼
actually makes him stressed.
反而对他有压力
It's fine.
没事的
How about we…
要不咱们把沈队给
It's only been a few days.
几天不见
Have you forgotten
你们是不是把我脾气
all about my temperament?
给忘了
Captain,
队长
what is your temperament?
你什么时候有脾气
Yeah.
就是
You're so boring.
你怎么那么无聊呢
But Captain Shen,
不过沈队
you suddenly returned,
突然归队
we're missing something.
是不是少点什么东西
What thing?
什么东西
Your comeback gift.
归队礼物啊
I'll sort it out for you right away.
这就给你策划
Way to go, Boss Du.
杜总可以啊
Cool.
可以
No matter how many difficulties I have to go through
不管经历多少困难
or how many obstacles I need to overcome,
克服多少阻碍
I'll always aim for the Olympics.
我都会冲击奥运
Sorry
对不起啊
that I let you down.
让你失望了
Be careful.
手都轻着点啊
These are expensive.
这东西可金贵着呢
Got it.
行
Don't worry, Coach.
放心吧 张教
Shen Qingyuan is fine.
沈清源没事
If anything isn't fine,
有事的啊
it's his crappy gun.
也就是他那把破枪
Oh, right, Coach.
对了 张教
You know I'm going
我这不是打算
to open a shooting club, right?
开射击俱乐部嘛
I purchased some new guns,
正好进了一批新枪
and I've also
沈队那支啊
got an upgrade for Captain Shen.
我一并帮他升级了
The gun was delivered this day.
今天啊就是运来了
Bro,
哥们
need any help?
需要帮忙吗
No.
不用了
Only the staff can touch these.
这事可不能让外人插手
I'm Zhou Yue, Captain of Southeast Team.
我是东南队的队长周越
Look.
你看看
I know the warehouse manager here
我们这边这库管啊
is bad-tempered.
人特别凶
And he always yells at you, right?
还总爱吼你们 是吧
You've been
我看你们这刚才
moving the boxes for some time.
都搬了好一会儿了
It's pretty tiring, right?
挺累的吧
I'll give you a hand.
我帮帮你们吧
You take a break,
你们休息一会儿
and you get to see that stinker less, right?
少受点他的气 是吧
Fine.
行
You need to be careful, though.
那你可得小心着点
Those are Haiya guns.
这是海雅那边的枪
If anything happens,
要是出了什么事
we'll be responsible.
我们可要负责到底
Don't worry. I got it.
放心 没问题啊
Okay. I appreciate it.
行 那辛苦你了
Thank you.
谢谢啊
Shen Qingyuan,
沈清源
without your gun,
没了枪
let's see how you'll do well.
我看你怎么发光发热
What are you doing?
你干吗呢
Shen Qingyuan, you're so dirty,
沈清源 你够阴的
aren't you?
你啊
Coach,
教练
they set up the snare
他们几个联合陷害我
for me to step in.
让我往里钻
I…
我
You what?
你 你什么呀你
You've disappointed me!
你太让我失望了
Liu,
老刘
you do what you have to do.
你看着办吧
Look what you've done.
看你干的好事
Give me that.
给我
Alright, alright.
好了 好了
Get on the bus. Get on the bus.
上车了 上车了
- Let's go.
走了 走了
Give me the bag.
把包给我
Will you?
给不给
You have three seconds.
我给你三秒钟
Quickly.
快点
- Let's go. - Be quick.
走了
Jiang Yitian.
江一天
You had it coming.
让你不给我
Attention. Attention.
注意 注意
Team leaders, coaches,
各领队 各教练
and athletes.
各运动员
Here's an announcement.
下面请听通知
Zhou Yue from Southeast Team
东南省队周越
has been suspended for a year
因违反管理规则
due to his violation of the regulations.
禁赛一年
- He's really suspended. - I repeat.
真禁赛了 重复一遍
Listen.
你听
Zhou Yue from Southeast Team
东南省队周越
has been suspended for a year
因违反管理规则
due to his violation of the regulations.
禁赛一年
Get on the bus.
走了上车了
Wait, let me put it in there.
等会儿 给我放一下
Put it in there.
放到里面
So it's sorted just like that?
就这么就解决了
Yeah.
是啊
I've been investigating him for a long time,
其实啊我查了他很久
but I never got anything on him.
但一直没抓住把柄
I had no choice
没办法
but to wait for him to expose himself.
只能等他自己暴露
Obviously,
说白了
he was driven mad by jealousy.
还是被忌妒冲昏了头脑
That's kind of
这样是不是
unethical, don't you think?
有点不道德呀
They're the indecent ones.
是他们自己行事不正
Even if we didn't do this,
就算我们不来这出
they'd be caught sooner or later.
他们迟早还得出事
Got it?
知道了吧
And look,
而且你看
even if he hadn't done this,
就算他没有这件事
they'd be in other trouble.
他们还肯定得出事
Why?
为什么呢
Because they're dishonorable.
因为他们人品不行
Karma will find them.
行得不正 肯定得摔跤
Right?
是吧
Nice job.
干得漂亮
He has a vile heart.
他心术不正
His eyes are evasive.
眼神都有点飘
You look at me, I look at you.
你看我 我看你
The formalities are excessive.
都点头哈点腰
Don't be hasty or you'll fall.
慢点你再摔了
You should watch over me.
你不看着我点
We're back at last.
终于回来了
Help me get
你帮我拿一下
that yellow luggage case.
我那黄箱子
Mine is the one inside.
我里面那个
Come on. Gather around, everyone.
来来来 过来一下
How do you feel to be back?
回来的感觉怎么样
- Good. - Great.
好 高兴
We'll keep training tomorrow.
明天开始继续训练啊
Go home and get some rest.
回去好好休息
Hello, Mr. Zhou.
喂 周总
- Bye, Coach.
教练再见
I'll see her together with you.
我跟您一起去见她吧
Let's dine together.
一起吃饭吧
Dine together?
一起吃饭
Okay, okay.
好啊 好啊 好啊
- We'll join you. - Us, too.
我们也去
Let's go together.
我们一起去吧
Yeah, together.
对啊 一起呗
(No.2 Canteen) I have to say
不得不说
that our campus canteen makes
还是咱们学校食堂的菜
great food.
好吃
It still can't compete with home cooking.
那能比得上那家私房菜
What?
干什么
Are you trying
是不是要挑拨
to turn me and Xiaoci against each other?
我跟小辞的关系
I warn you...
我警告你啊
Enough.
行了
Let's talk business.
说正事吧
As planned previously,
按照正常的时间顺序呢
I should be processing
我也得开始
my quit from now on.
办退队手续了
So please
所以请大家珍惜
cherish the final days with me.
现在跟我相处的时间
When will you leave?
你什么时候走啊
Normally, the process
正常办手续的话
takes about a week.
大概一周吧
We'll miss you.
我们会想你的
I forgot about the short video.
把短片给忘了
I hope I can finish it in time.
希望时间还来得及
Tang Xin,
唐心
if you have a minute,
什么时候方便的话
please come to see me in the Counseling Room.
来一下心理咨询室吧
Coach, Dr. Ding.
教练 丁医生
Hi, Tang Xin.
来了 唐心
Sit.
坐吧
Tang Xin,
唐心
although Shen Qingyuan has returned to the team,
沈清源呢虽然归队了
Coach Zhang
但是张教练
is still pretty concerned.
他一直非常地焦虑
He didn't want to interfere with his winter training,
之前怕影响他冬训
so he never let it out.
所以一直憋着没说
Now that he's back in the university,
但既然现在已经回校了
we'd like to learn
就想从你这儿了解一下
if Shen Qingyuan is willing
沈清源他后续
to take the follow-up treatment.
接受治疗的意愿
After all, he hasn't
毕竟他现在
got his entire memory back yet.
还没有完全恢复记忆
What if
要是
he suddenly runs away again?
他再突然跑走了怎么办
Let's learn his state
到底怎么样
from Tang Xin first.
还是听小唐说吧
Ever since he recovered from the outbreak,
从那之后到现在
I haven't noticed anything abnormal about him.
我没觉得他有什么异常
Has he shown any sign
那他最近
of remembering anything?
有没有想起什么的迹象
When will you
那你准备
tell him
什么时候跟他提
about the official clinical psychotherapy?
正式接受治疗的事
Dr. Ding,
丁医生
is there an adjuvant
有没有什么辅助性
treatment method?
治疗的办法呢
Although
他现在
he seems normal at the moment,
虽然没有什么异常
(Schedule of Trial for National Training Team) I'm worried that…
但我怕他之后
When it comes to a patient
对于沈清源
like Shen Qingyuan,
这样的患者而言呢
before he retrieves
在他没有完全找回
and accepts his memory about the past,
和接纳从前的记忆之前
uncertainties always exist.
就始终都有隐患
So I can't
所以必须
make a diagnosis
要让他来接受治疗
before he takes the psychotherapy.
我才好判断
I'm worried that I may provoke him
我怕跟他提到治疗
by mentioning psychotherapy.
会刺激到他
Tang Xin,
小唐
we don't have time.
咱没有时间了
It's only one month
还有一个月
before the trial for the national team.
就是国家队选拔赛
If he can't be selected,
如果这次选不上
he'll never get another chance to participate in the Olympics.
就彻底和奥运无缘了
So Shen Qingyuan…
那沈清源
I haven't signed him up yet.
我现在还没有给他报名
If he isn't in the best state,
如果他的状态不好
he'll only squander the opportunity.
去了也是浪费名额
Coach Zhang, trust me.
张教练 您放心吧
I understand our priority
我明白首要原则
is that he
还是要让他
participates in the games.
能够参加比赛
Tang Xin,
唐心
too much concern brings trouble.
关心则乱
You saw
你见过他
the worst situation of his,
情况最严重的时候
so I'm sure you understand
所以一定明白
the importance of psychotherapy.
治疗的必要性
Dr. Ding,
丁医生
I know what you mean.
我明白你的意思
May I find
那我可不可以找一个
a better time to talk to him?
更合适的时机呢
I understand your concern.
我知道你的顾虑
And maybe
说不好
it'll even slow down his recovery.
反而会影响他的恢复
But postponement
但是拖太久了
will only lead to more uncertainties.
终究夜长梦多
I'll leave you to your conversation.
那你们先聊着
Don't worry, Coach Zhang.
放心吧 张教练
This is the detailed rule for the national team to select athletes.
这是国家队的选拔细则
Have a look.
你看一下
I know that you aim
我知道你的目标
for the Olympics,
是奥运会
but you won't have a chance
但首先要进入国家队
unless you get into the national team.
你才有机会
So your time
所以接下来的时间
is short.
很紧迫
You need to get your game state back.
你要抓紧找回你的状态
I understand.
我明白
Shen,
小沈
I'm not trying to put pressure on you.
我不是给你压力啊
As a shooter,
你是练射击的
you should know
你应该知道
that there's no turning back
子弹一出枪膛
for a shot-out bullet.
就没有回头路
So before you shoot,
所以你在射击之前
make sure you have no regret.
要做到心中无悔
Every shot has to be confident.
每一枪都要打得有底气
Looking back at your past
回过头直面往事
requires courage.
这更需要勇气
But it will grant you power, too.
也会更加给你力量
In a sense,
从某种意义上来讲
Shen Qingyuan is lucky.
沈清源他是幸运的
Because he has got you.
因为他有你在
Thank you, Dr. Ding.
谢谢丁医生
Dr. Ding,
丁医生
you said you wanted
您之前说想出一本
to write a book about
关于运动员
athletes' mental health.
心理健康的书
May I help you with it?
我可以参与进来吗
How?
怎么
You'd like
你想分享
to share the story between you and Shen Qingyuan?
你跟沈清源的故事
This is what I have in mind for now.
我目前是这么想的
But I haven't asked for his opinion.
但我还没有问过他
If I'm given the permission,
那如果可以的话
I'd like to share our true story
分享真实经历
so that more of those in need
可以让更多
can see it.
有需要的人看到
It's a form of consolation, at least.
至少也是一种安慰嘛
Thank you for your goodwill,
谢谢你的心意啊
Tang Xin.
唐心
I also would like
我呢
to make a series of videos
还想做一系列的视频
and post them online.
放到网上
And when your book is published,
到时候配合您的书
I think they will
应该可以让更多
reach more people in need.
有需要的人看到
Good idea.
好主意
She's the one you've been expecting?
你等的人是她
Tang Xin,
唐心
sit.
坐
Thank you.
谢谢
Want some drink?
要不要点点喝的
No.
不用了
Let's put the past aside
以前的事啊
for now.
咱们先放一放
Ai,
小艾
after all,
毕竟
I came to ask you for a favor.
今天我是来求你帮忙的
And this thing
而且这件事情
is related to Tang Xin.
跟唐心也有关系
Shall we begin?
那我们能开始了吗
Okay.
好
The one from Tonight Show?
这不是今夜有约的
Yes.
对
Xu Dian is a habitual criminal.
徐典是个惯犯
To him,
在他眼里
all beautiful young girls
年轻漂亮的女孩
are his prey.
就是猎物
Or his toys
是玩具
that have no value.
没有任何价值
And you're not the only one
而且受到伤害的
who was harmed.
也不是你一个人
I'll give you an example.
我说个例子吧
A few years back
前几年
when I still worked in the TV station,
我还在电视台的时候
I was in charge of several programs
在体育频道
on the sports channel.
负责几个栏目
At the time, I brought up a female presenter.
当时培养了一个女主持
Who was like you,
就跟你一样
studious, diligent,
勤奋 踏实
and got potential.
而且很有潜力
But on the day before
但是在一档直播节目的
a livestream program was on air,
开播前一天
she suddenly quit her job.
她突然罢工离职
She walked away without leaving a word.
一句话没说就走了
No matter how hard I tried to contact her,
不管我怎么联系她
she wouldn't see me.
她都不肯见我
I always thought
我一直以为
I'd done something wrong,
是我做错了什么事
or maybe
或者干脆
I'd put my faith in the wrong person.
就是我看错了人
The program experienced a crisis,
当时节目出了重大事故
and I was accountable for it.
这个责任必须由我来背
So I had been demoted
所以我被降职到了
to Rui Live.
锐直播
I never knew that.
原来是这样
That's not important.
这些都不重要
It wasn't until I met Xu Dian
直到这次冬训
at the winter training
我遇到了徐典
did I figure it
才把事情的来龙去脉
all out.
弄清楚
She left the TV station
她是被徐典性骚扰
out of anger
才一气之下
because Xu Dian committed sexual harassment on her.
离开了电视台
So Ai,
所以小艾
do not trust Xu Dian anymore.
不要再相信徐典了
He won't
他不会兑现
fulfill any compromise that he made.
他的任何承诺
I know.
我知道
Because Tonight Show
因为今夜有约
is what
就是他答应过
he promised me.
给我的节目
You're lucky.
你真走运
I always believe that you fight
我一直相信任何事情
to earn everything in life.
都要靠自己努力的
You think I don't believe so?
你以为我不相信吗
You think I was like this
你以为我从一开始
from the beginning?
就是现在这样吗
You met Zhou Zuguang
你遇到的是周祖光
while I met Xu Dian.
我遇到的是徐典
This is the most unfair part.
这就是最大的不公平
Do you know
你知道
how it feels
被徐典这样的人缠着
to fight against
我一个人抵抗
Xu Dian's harassment on my own?
是什么滋味吗
It almost feels like I don't have a future anymore.
就感觉前途快要毁了
No one would listen to me
没有人会听我
or trust me
信我
or even remember me.
甚至记住我
He'll never get off my back.
只有他会一直缠着我
If you only have two choices,
如果你面前只有两条路
reject him
拒绝
and go home,
回老家
or accept it
接受
in exchange of a chance to climb up,
有机会往上爬
what would you choose?
你怎么选
But he's lying to you.
可他是在骗你的
You think you're the only smart one, huh?
就你聪明啊
Now that I've taken the path,
即使走上这条路
even though I know, I have to pretend that I don't.
知道也要装作不知道
Do you understand?
你懂吗
There's no way back for me.
我没有退路
But now you
可你现在
still have another choice.
依然有条路可以选
Ai,
小艾
you're a smart girl.
你是个聪明的姑娘
I believe you take precautions
你一直陪在徐典旁边
while you're with Xu Dian,
不会不做准备的
right?
对吗
Or else you wouldn't have come here.
不然你也不会来这儿
This is all I have.
我有的都在这儿了
The recommendation letter that you promised me,
你答应过给我的推荐信
don't you forget that.
你别忘了
No problem.
这个没问题
That's a nice city.
那个城市还不错
You'll have a nice life there.
你可以在那儿好好生活
It's none of your concern.
不用你管
I'm home.
我回来了
Welcome home.
欢迎回家
Put the slippers on.
换拖鞋吧
I got them ready for you.
给你放好了
And him.
还有它
He welcomes your return, too.
它也欢迎你回来
I never thought one day,
没想到有一天
I'd have two of my lovers on both sides.
我也可以左拥右抱
Just me, please.
抱我就好
Well done, Shen Qingyuan.
干得不错 沈清源
Your praise
你这个表扬
sounds insincere.
有点过于形式主义了
Insincere how?
我哪里有形式主义呀
This is a praise
我是多么充满热情
full of passion and sincerity.
又质朴的赞美
Shen Qingyuan,
沈清源
you want the praise
你是不是想要
in the form of material, right?
实质性的表扬啊
So to an athlete,
那作为运动员来说
is the praise in the form of material
实质性的表扬
a gold medal?
是不是金牌呢
To be precise,
准确地来说
yes, a gold medal,
是金牌
and you.
还有你
I haven't signed him up yet.
我还没有给他报名
If he isn't in the best state,
如果他的状态不好
he'll only squander the opportunity.
去了也是浪费名额
I bought you a gift.
我给你买了礼物
It'll soon arrive.
一会儿就到
I'll go change to something comfortable.
我去换身舒服的衣服
How come
我怎么
I put on Shen Qingyuan's T-shirt?
穿了沈清源的T恤
Never mind. I'll keep it on.
算了 先凑合穿吧
I'll go change it in my bedroom.
回卧室再换
Tang Xin,
唐心
the noodles are ready.
来吃面
Let it cool down.
你先晾凉吧
I'll have it when it's less hot.
你晾凉了我再吃
You eat noodles when it's hot,
面就要趁热吃
right?
是不是
I'm not wearing a suitable T-shirt.
我衣服不合适
I'll go change it.
我先去换个衣服
No.
没有
It suits you perfectly.
很合适
Is it good?
好吃吗
I give you this.
这个
Good to know.
那就好
Won't you eat some?
你不吃吗
I've had some.
我吃过了
I'll just watch.
我看你吃就好
Look at you.
你看你
You're so careless.
怎么吃这么不小心啊
Shen Qingyuan,
沈清源
I think we'd better
我们下次
dine together.
还是一起吃饭吧
Why?
为什么一起吃
Because you keep disturbing me
因为你不吃饭没事做
when you're not eating.
就会一直骚扰我啊
The gift has arrived.
应该是礼物到了
Don't go.
你别去了
I'll go get it.
我去拿吧
Why?
为什么
Your T-shirt is not suitable.
你穿这样不合适
You just said it suited me perfectly.
你刚刚还说挺合适的呀
Because only I'm the only one who gets to see you.
那是在我面前
It's for you.
送你的
It's a bit childish, isn't it?
是不是太幼稚了点
Forget it, then.
不要算了
I love childish stuff.
我就喜欢幼稚的
Actually, I bought one for myself, too.
其实我也给自己
With a doll on it.
买了一只洋娃娃的
So not only did the doll and the bear
所以洋娃娃跟小熊
dance together,
不仅仅跳了舞
but they also…
它们还
Shen Qingyuan,
沈清源
you're unbelievable.
你现在真的是
I said nothing.
我什么都没说
Actually,
其实
you are right.
你说得也没错
What I mean is,
我的意思就是呢
if you accept the pillow,
你如果收了这只枕头
maybe
或许
we can go to my room and…
可以来我的房间一起
Come on, then.
走吧
Wait. Wait a minute.
等等 等一下
You just said
你刚才不还说
it was a childish pillow
这只枕头幼稚
and that you didn't want it.
不想要吗
I said,
我说了啊
I love childish stuff.
我就喜欢幼稚的
And this pillow
而且这个枕头
is the warmest pillow in the world.
是世界上最温暖的枕头
Oh, right, Shen Qingyuan.
对了 沈清源
I'd like to
有件事情
discuss something with you.
想跟你商量一下
What?
你说
Can our story
以后我们俩的事情
go public in the future?
我可以公开吗
Yours, mine.
你的 我的
Ours.
我们共同的
Why?
为什么
Though I'm not sure,
虽然不知道有没有用
I hope it will be helpful
但希望可以帮助到
for those who had similar experiences.
更多相同遭遇的人
Okay.
好